# **Bobby Schaetzle**

## Summary

Entrepreneurial minded software engineer with over twenty years' experience, a creative approach to problem solving, and the ambition to push the possibilities of programming to the limit.

I get great joy out of building things, and constantly surround myself with an assortment of half-built programs to work on when the moment strikes. I like to be challenged, and gravitate towards projects with enough depth and variety to expand and enhance my skill set. I learn best by doing and am able to absorb new technology very quickly, especially when working in a self-directed environment.

In addition to my experience and passion, with me as your engineer I'll bring the determination to get the job done, no matter what it is.

#### Skills

	1-2 years	2-5 years	5+ years
Languages		Python, JavaScript,	Java, Perl, SQL, XML,
		SASS, XSLT,	HTML, CSS, LPC
		Freemarker	
Libraries	Node.js, jQuery,	Spring Framework, ZK	
	Bootstrap, Dust.js,	Web Framework	
	WebSockets. Hibernate		
Tools	NoSQL (MongoDB)	Jenkins CI	Git/GitHub,
			Subversion, Maven,
			JIRA, Linux
Other		Service-oriented	Agile methodologies,
		architecture	game design, e-
			commerce

#### Experience

## October 2015 - present

#### **PavPal**

San Jose, CA

- Senior engineer in PayPal's Global Platform Services group. Developed lightweight web applications to provide user interfaces for various services on the PayPal Platform-as-a-Service application stack, including Cache as a Service, CookieServ, and WebCrawler. Worked independently, owning all code from the front-end (CSS/Bootstrap, JQuery, Dust.js templates) to mid-tier (Node.js/Kraken, MongoDB), interfacing with backend services via REST.
- Served on the UNP (Unified Notification Platform) team as an individual contributor, participating in story work for UNP Java components and the Node.js-based UNP dashboard.

## July 2010 - May 2015

#### Williams-Sonoma, Inc.

San Francisco, CA

- Contracted staff software engineer for a large-scale Spring web application providing e-commerce solutions for six diverse brands. Designed and developed code across the data modelling, business logic, activity API, and user interface layers of the stack, collaborating closely with architecture, devops and production support teams to ensure reliability and longevity of finished products.
- Projects encompassed a broad range of site functionality, including product browse and search paths, home and feature pages, and shopping cart, checkout and registry forms.
- Projects also included the integration of several third-party solutions, including Endeca for search
  and faceted navigation, BorderFree for international shipping and currency conversion, and
  Akamai for content caching.
- Active participant in the adoption and adherence to Agile software development methodologies, and efforts to maximize the utility of the Atlassian suite of collaboration and productivity tools.

## September 2009 - November 2009

## Williams-Sonoma, Inc.

#### San Francisco, CA

- Short-term contract to develop a single-use application for the migration of product catalog data from a legacy spreadsheet-based system to a new content management system (Adobe CQ) based on the Content Repository API for Java (JCR 2.0).
- Data migration was performed in Python (Jython) and consisted of two endpoints, one an XML dump from the legacy system and the other the new repository, accessed via the Apache Jackrabbit Java library.

• Development and testing was completed before schedule, allowing additional optimizations to be made which reduced the time necessary to perform the migration, as well as the development of a web-based user interface, alleviating the complexity of the command-line interface.

# August 2008 - July 2009 BlueArc San Jose, CA

- Developed a web-based user interface for the management of a hardware-accelerated network storage appliance. Most projects were comprised of first modelling SOAP calls, then implementing SOAP endpoints, in C++ on the backend appliance and in Java in the management application. The business logic and presentation layer were built on an Apache Turbine stack using the Velocity template engine.
- Collaborated in the production of a new hardware platform, shifting from the existing multi-system
  architecture to a single-system, embedded management unit running in a traditional Linux
  environment. This required major changes to the packaging and deployment processes, as well as
  integration with newly conceived middleware responsible for bridging the gap between Linux and
  a proprietary BlueArc Operating System.
- Development was heavily dependent on very costly hardware of which there were limited resources available. As a result, the job required more operational tasks than a typical software engineer role might entail, with significant time spent setting up, maintaining, and troubleshooting hardware concerns.

## March 2007 - May 2008 Teneros, Inc. Mountain View, CA

- Senior engineer on the user interface team for application continuity appliances (ACAs), developing two distinct web applications to support them; one, a Python-based customer-facing application which ran on the ACA providing installation and management functions, the other a large-scale Java Enterprise application which ran in the Network Operations Center (NOC) to monitor devices *en masse* out in the field.
- Ramped up quickly to lead role for projects utilizing many technologies just emerging at the time, or were otherwise unknown to me upon beginning the job. Some of these technologies include the ZK Ajax Web application framework, configuration-based MVC frameworks, Hibernate and ORM, JBoss and EJB3, AspectJ and AOP, JFlex and lexical analysis, and Apache Maven. The job also introduced me to design patterns, refactoring, and was my first multi-threaded application.
- Because the appliance functioned as a failover device for Microsoft Exchange services, great emphasis was placed on reliability and infrequent intervention by the end user during standby operation.

## February 2003 - December 2006 Williams-Sonoma, Inc. San Francisco, CA

- Learned the anatomy of an e-commerce application; belonged to the web development team, participating in three platform migrations in three years.
- For the first, already underway upon joining the development team, wrote ColdFusion code to bring the six independent brand sites together onto a common core, with only presentation layer code implemented specifically for each brand.
- For the second, a migration to the IBM Global Services e-commerce solution which was eventually abandoned, stepped back into mostly a supporting role, developing minor releases for and otherwise maintaining the legacy ColdFusion sites.
- For the last, moved into a leadership role to bring the legacy sites onto the latest Java-based ColdFusion platform, and to refactor various common presentation layer logic up into the core codebase, and to add configuration-driven front-end behavior available at the content management level in the form of document metadata.

Worked on the web engineering team for java.sun.com, the team tasked primarily with staging new
Java releases on the web site. Transitioned to a developer role when requested to retool the Perl
scripts for the file download tunnel to use a different backend, the one used by the "Sun Download
Center," an e-commerce suite used by other divisions of the company.

#### October 1996 - October 1998

#### FriendFinder Networks

Palo Alto, CA

• First programming job; learned Perl upon joining, the only prior experience being amateur LPC programming. Also learned how to take assignments and build software to someone's specifications; sometimes this came as very precise instructions, "write a script that turns this text into this other text," and sometimes broad, "reverse engineer geocities.com."

#### Education

#### August 1998 - December 2000

San Francisco State University

San Francisco, CA

Bachelor of Arts degree in Cinema.

## **September 1995 - June 1998**

De Anza College

Cupertino, CA

• Associate of Arts degree in Film/Television Production.

## **Organizations**

## August 2008 - present

## untitled gamification platform

- Founder of a new platform on which to build gamified systems. Open-source, hosted by GitHub, using the LDMud engine, Node.js, and WebSockets.
- Attempts to establish an integration layer on which to model the different components of some
  game-like experience. Defines a taxonomy of different kinds of game objects and spaces, physics
  which govern how different game components may interact, and support for different gaming
  instruments like currency, achievements, quests, leader boards, group play and collaboration, and
  levels.
- Also offers a model for advancement through the game system through the use of narrative and narrative devices, and provides managerial tools to influence emergent behavior and to engineer social experiences to fit familiar game patterns.

## February 1994 - present

## **End of the Line LPMud**

- Learned how to program on End of the Line LPMud (EotL), a text-based multi-player online roleplaying game, using a byte-compiled object-oriented language with C-like syntax called LPC. Helped build core game components and libraries, and served in a senior game designer role.
- Experiences on EotL serve as the foundation for my gamification work, I still actively collaborate with the other users there to solve the problems of a MUD in the modern era.